<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patrick Rogan | Digital Designer</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 18:12:39 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 18:12:39 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Case Page</title>
        <description>&lt;article class=&quot;case-header&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;case-header-logo&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;cs-logo&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;../img/sf/sixfusion.svg&quot;&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;		
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;case-header-summary&quot;&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;6Fusion reached out to me to conduct a refresh for the new iteration of their web app that leveraged their existing brand, while providing a user experience that allows the user to view and process a large amount of data at a glance.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;case-header-image&quot;&gt;
		&lt;img src=&quot;../img/sf/sixfusion-hero.png&quot;&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;

&lt;section class=&quot;sf-green&quot;&gt;
	&lt;div class=&quot;container&quot;&gt;
		&lt;div class=&quot;retina-scale&quot;&gt;
			&lt;img src=&quot;../img/sf/sixfusion-typography.png&quot;&gt;
		&lt;/div&gt;
	&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/case</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/case</guid>
        
        
        <category>case</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creativity is Dangerous</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to challenge you to do something seemingly unprecedented: Stop being creative. Don’t think outside the box. Don’t do anything. Instead I want you to take a moment to ponder what it means to be a “Product Designer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;product designer&lt;/strong&gt; |&lt;em&gt;ˈprädəkt dəˈzīnər&lt;/em&gt;|
noun
a person who plans the form, look, and/or workings of an article or substance that is manufactured or refined to provide a solution towards a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of us became designers because we were intrigued by visual solutions. We weren’t aware that this is what they were, mind you. We merely wanted to be part of a technological revolution that allowed us to create them. It wasn’t until it became more than a hobby and bloomed into a career that we realized how important our roles as pioneers are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a designer, you are enlisted with using your creativity to solve problems. Your primary objective is to distill proposed solutions into a viable infrastructure. This is where discipline comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In my experience, excellent design is rarely about creating something new. The so-called flash-of-brilliance isn’t about invention. It’s about distillation. It feels so strikingly simple. It doesn’t feel new. It feels like it should have always been that way. Knowing that, I would argue that the best designs come from discipline, not creativity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a small trend in our industry towards designing award winning designs. Clients often see it as an opportunity to gain exposure and some designers see it as a means of bragging rights. The moment I hear a client mention among many other buzz-words that they are looking for a ground-breaking award winning website design, I feel the world shake as designers worldwide collectively drop bricks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t compromise a solution’s integrity over&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There is this old saying. “You need to know the rules before you break them”. It’s not surprising that people who’ve just started in our industry feel tempted the most to create fancy designs and interactions. These are the designs that often get awwwards, and yet these are the ones many users struggle the most with.”`&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/essays/creativity-is-dangerous</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/essays/creativity-is-dangerous</guid>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
        <category>essay</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Lingering: Act I</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;They say that life flashes before your eyes moments before your death. Too bad everyone qualified to verify this well known myth is part of the collective gathering of ungrateful dead of which I am soon to become a part of. I only wish I’d had a more dignified death. If only my killer weren’t so silent and unapologetically self-righteous. In short, I am getting clobbered to death by a red-light running motherfucking Prius.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Shit…” I sigh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s about it. I don’t even swear unless I’m pissy drunk. I feel as though if I had been, I’d at least have some remotely epic last words other than shit. I need more time to think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If that’s what you want…” I hear a voice say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fall on my knees, only to feel concern over my dress becoming soiled on the dirty pavement. Yes. Out of all things to be worried at my time of death, it’s got to be my dress. Hey, getting hit by cars only to have time slow down is quite commonplace compared to a soiled dress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mother is going to kill me…” I mutter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Too late…” Says the voice again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except it wasn’t  just any voice. It was &lt;em&gt;his&lt;/em&gt; voice. Of course it is. There we go. This is it. The part where I start thinking of the person I love most before I die. Why am I surprised at the magnificent asshole invading my head once again?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Magnificent asshole, you say? I’m flattered to see that you find me magnificent even in my assholery.” he continu–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wait. Did he just read my mind? Oh, wait, of course he did. He’s a figment of my-&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Imaginaaaatoin” he interrupts. “See what I did there? It was a SpongeBob reference. It’s funny, because it’s relevant and I mispelt it just to make the grammar nazis reading this squirm.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Huh?” I reply, stunned, my attention still held firmly on the now sluggish car still headed in my direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I broke the fourth wa– You know what? Never mind. Look at me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Huh…? Oh.” and ‘Oh’ indeed. There he was. The magnificent asshole that was Locksley crouching next to me with his usual air of smugness.
He pulls out a bottle of rum and offers me some. I refuse. Last time I remotely touched alcohol my frail body convulsed as though I’d been shown the holy grail of candy shops as a child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oooh. That’s a sexy memory. If wine does that to you… Just imagine what we could do on one of your beds. Which, by the way, I know you prefer sleeping on the floor (for whatever God-given reason), but wouldn’t it be more efficient to just get rid of one of your beds?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He continues talking like this for about two minutes. Normally I wouldn’t be able to stop laughing, but I didn’t even smile. Normally I wouldn’t be able to break eye contact with him unless I were blushing violently, and yet, I looked away. Under normal circumstances, I wouldn’t be able to slap him as fucking hard as I just did, but these weren’t exactly normal circumstances, and he was, as a matter of fact, an asshole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh. My. Word. I just slapped Locksley. Really hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Took you long enough,” he replied after a few moments. His glance now vacant and lost in the stars. “Let’s go get coffee.”
And just like that he got up, dusted himself off, and offered me a hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Please…?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How dare he show his face here again. After I told him to leave my life. How dare he do this to me. I don’t care if this is nothing but a hallucination. I don’t want to see him ever again.
“Okay,” I reply and take his hand.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-lingering/chapter-01</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-lingering/chapter-01</guid>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
        <category>the-lingering</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Ubiquitous Web</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you were to look back at the origins of the web, you’d see a fledgling entity trying to discover its place in the world. Code was without semantics and design without purpose. We were, of course, like a child who’d just realized they could dress on their own, but had no sense for coordination in style and fashion. It’s come quite a long way since then, to the extent that it touches almost every aspect of our modern life. An absence of connection to the web, to most, feels like an absence of connection to the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it’s only a foundation. Unlike a physical foundation, the web is liquid, and able and willing to transform within the hands of its crafters. It’s your individual choice as to whether you need to put yet another hero image for your latest project or make it a fully interactive experience. Claiming everyone’s site out there looks the same is like wondering why everyone is driving a Corolla: It’s a reliable car and it just works. Frameworks like Bootstrap allow developers who are less inclined towards design to build upon something that can later be easily understood and expanded upon by others who can embrace the role of design more fluently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, we can either complain that every site out there looks the same or we can complain that everyone’s site looks like shit. I however, choose to do neither. As product designers, it is our role to build custom solutions to suit our clients and/or user base. That may mean we needing to stay conservative. There’s no need to slow down development for the sake of flairs and whistles that are harder to mantain. That can also mean it’s your role to create an out of the box solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ubiquity arises after a proven and tried method has been established, but it doesn’t mean it’s our limit. It merely means our forefathers paved the way for the simplicity we are endowed with today. Let’s accept… Let’s accept it and exceed it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2015 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/essay/the-ubiquitous-web</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/essay/the-ubiquitous-web</guid>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
        <category>essay</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
